POONAM AHIR

Email: poonamahir96@gmail.com

Cell Phone: (705) 988-4030

Linked: https://www.linkedin.com/in/poonam-ahir-43912b17a/

SUMMARY

Motivated, team-oriented, responsible professional with experience in a variety of complex and comprehensive projects ranging from website generation to medical data analysis to developing best practices for ERP transactions in a global organization. I have a Masters in Computational Science and experience working with a number of different systems. I work well in a team, an effective communicator has experience managing staff.

KEY SKILLS AND CHARACTERISTICS

Microsoft Office Suite
Machine learning
C, C++, R Language, Python
Power BI, SQL, SAP

Problem Solving Work Prioritization

Critical Thinking

Handling Pressure

Leadership

Conflict Resolution Techniques

Technical Proficiency

EXPERIENCE

General Assistant Manager, Moonlight Inn & Suits, Sudbury, ON January 2024 – Present

- Assisting in the overall management of hotel operations.
- Overseeing and coordinating day-to-day activities to ensure exceptional guest experiences.
- Managing and supervising hotel staff to maintain a high standard of service.
- Handling customer inquiries, concerns, and complaints effectively and promptly.
- Collaborating with other departments to ensure seamless hotel operations

External Resource Management Administrator, Vale, Copper cliff, ON

June 2023 - August 2023

• Develop and generate requisitions for the creation of continuous contract agreements.

- Create purchase orders and enter service entry sheets to generate payments for vendor invoices.
- Review invoice details against contract agreements to ensure charges are in accordance with the commercial terms.
- Address any issues promptly with the vendors / internal users to ensure quick resolution and no delay in payment process.
- Accountable for ensuring payment process is complete including system checks for invoice payment status, identifying root cause issues and implementing solutions
- Manage relationships with vendors and internal users to work through any issues relating to the requisition to payment process.
- Full participation in safety routines and adherence to HomeSafe principles during daily activities.

Controls Specialist, (fixed term) Vale, Copper cliff, ON

August 2022 – May 2023

- Provide analytical support to the department to enable the evaluation of financial outcomes, value drivers and risks. Work with the team to develop appropriate control systems that act as early warning mechanisms to identify variances to targets in sufficient time to remedy.
- Contribute to the development of new financial processes or the improvement of existing financial processes as required.
- Track and report on departmental Key Performance Indicators (KPI)
- Coordinate the collection of operating, maintenance, services, supplies and other data as required to support strategy decisions and regular reporting routines.
- Develop, monitor and evaluate SAP and Business Objects reports to assist the Contractor Performance Management Area using Power Bi and SAP.
- Support continuous improvement routines and problem-solving initiatives using the VPS framework.
- Build and cultivate internal and external business relationships.
- Participate in all required safety training and apply the principles of HomeSafe during daily tasks.

Customer service Manager, Walmart Sudbury, ON

2018- Present – Part time flex

- Reviewing reports to establish baseline customer satisfaction levels.
- Contacting customers who have complained and work with them to resolve their issues.
- Promoting a positive work environment for employees and leading by example.
- Managing staffing levels for the customer service counter and other key areas.
- Ensuring associates are adequately trained and up to date on current procedures.

- Overseeing cashiers, filling and switching up cash registers, scheduling cashiers' breaks, assigning associates to a cashier role when the store is too busy, etc.
- Accountable for coaching, development and general safety of staff
- Various other front-end operations.

Graduate Teaching assistant, Laurentian University Sudbury, ON 2018 Septembers - 2020 April

- Communicate virtually with computer users experiencing difficulties to determine and document problems.
- Reproduce technical problems encountered by users.
- On call troubleshooting for User experience support. Conduct quiz section meetings, maintain webpage for course materials, Attend TA training meetings, review literature.

EDUCATION

Masters in Computational Science, Laurentian University, Sudbury, ON August 2021

During my master's degree I have successfully completed my thesis ("Semi Supervised learning for pancreas cancer survival analysis") and four courses with B grade.

Bachelors in Computer science, Gujarat Technological University, India May 2017

PROJECTS

Semi supervised learning for pancreas cancer survival analysis

Treated the high dimensional data using $L_{1/2}$ regularization. Implemented four methods of Single Cox, Single AFT, Semi-supervised Cox and Semi-supervised AFT have been used to implement survival analysis and the aim of the simulation study was to compare the four models in correctly detecting the prognostic genes.

I-Field Sprinkler

ANDROID APPLICATION ON "I- FIELD SPRINKLER"

It is a soil sensing based automated watering system integrated with microcontroller (Raspberry

Pi), Soil Moisture Sensor, Ultrasonic Sensor, GSM Module, Solenoid Valve and Pump

Front end: ANDROID Backend: MY SQL

Android: ANDROID STUDIO

Hardware: PYTHON PROGRAMMING

Online Government certificate generator

Developed a website to generate government certificate to be produce for different welfare and education requirement for the students and citizens. The applicant requests the certificate online though my system and request the certificate online. After the request the system redirect the request to relevant authority in the government department and after verification and confirmation the authority will confirm the details of the applicant and then only the application will be able to download the certificate from the site. The technology used for this application is to develop a website in ASP.net and backend in MYSQL for online government certificate generation.